{
  "categories": [
    {
      "category_name": "English",
      "number_of_questions": 40,
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question_text": "I like ………… in my spare time",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "reading"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "read"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "to read"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "to reading"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "reading"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question_text": "I went to the bookshop .................... 'Harry Potter'.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "For buying"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "to buy"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "to buying"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "for to buy"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "to buy"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question_text": "He is interested ......... learning Romanian.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "in"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "on"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "to"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "for"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "in"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question_text": "Would you like …. …. … to drink, Sir ?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "anything"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "anywhere"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "nothing"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "something"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "anything"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question_text": "What ………. next weekend?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "do you do"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "are you doing"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "will you do"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "did you do"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "are you doing"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question_text": "How many students in your class ………. from Bangladesh?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "comes"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "come"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "came"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "are coming"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "come"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question_text": "I am hungry. I want two …….. of chicken .",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "plates"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "pieces"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "bowls"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "gasses"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "pieces"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question_text": "They are ugly and expensive; ……. ….. people buy them",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "though"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "yet"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "still"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "besides"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "though"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question_text": "What time .....",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "the train leaves?"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "leaves the train?"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "is the train leaving?"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "does the train leave?"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "does the train leave?"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question_text": "I promise I .................. study harder.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "will"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "am going to"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "may"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "must"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "will"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question_text": "How long ……………………. English?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "are you learning"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "have you been learning"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "do you learn"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "you learn"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "have you been learning"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question_text": "I hope that a school ……. For village children",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "opens"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "is opened"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "has to be opened"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "be opened"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "is opened"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question_text": "Closest similar meaning of word ‘compunction’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "remorse"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "merciful"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "connive"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "recklessness"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "remorse"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question_text": "Closest similar meaning of word ‘demolish’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "repair"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "consume"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "humiliate"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "destroy"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "destroy"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question_text": "Closest similar meaning of word ‘beneficent’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "charitable"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "imagery"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "profitable"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "cost-effective"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "charitable"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question_text": "Closest similar meaning of word ‘mendacity’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "mandatory"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "untruthfulness"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "veracity"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "potential"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "untruthfulness"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question_text": "Closest opposite meaning of word ‘theocracy’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "hierocracy"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "ideology"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "conservative"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "church state"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "hierocracy"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question_text": "Closest opposite meaning of word ‘integrate’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "accommodate"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "compose"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "articulate"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "segregate"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "segregate"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question_text": "Closest opposite meaning of word ‘Calm’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "excited"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "restful"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "cool"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "serene"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "excited"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question_text": "Closest opposite meaning of word ‘wordy’ is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "rambling"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "concise"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "diffuse"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "voluble"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "concise"
        },
        {
          "id": 21,
          "question_text": "A teacher needs to discuss in classes, it ____________ curiosity in students.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "creates"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "created"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "create"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "will creates"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "creates"
        },
        {
          "id": 22,
          "question_text": "Successful people always __________ two things: one, determination and second, sincerity.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "had"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "doing"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "did"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "have"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "have"
        },
        {
          "id": 23,
          "question_text": "They like swimming, whenever they have a leisure time. (Which word is a verbal noun?)",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Leisure"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "free"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "like"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "swimming"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "swimming"
        },
        {
          "id": 24,
          "question_text": "Nobody likes heap of garbage in front of his house. (Which word is a collective noun?)",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "leap of garbage"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "in front"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "house"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "likes"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "leap of garbage"
        },
        {
          "id": 25,
          "question_text": "Find interrogative pronoun in sentence \"Why did you not call me.? This made me alarmed.\"",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "you"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "me"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "why"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "did"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "why"
        },
        {
          "id": 26,
          "question_text": "Right grammatical category of the underlined phrase in the sentence “ Ram handed a book to his sister” is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "complement"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "direct object"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "adjunct"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "indirect object"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "indirect object"
        },
        {
          "id": 27,
          "question_text": "Which of the following is noun?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "real"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "readable"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "reliable"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "reality"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "reality"
        },
        {
          "id": 28,
          "question_text": "English is today the third ………… native language worldwide after Chinese and Hindi, with some 380 million speakers.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "the most spoken"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "the more spoken"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "much spoken"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "most spoken"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "most spoken"
        },
        {
          "id": 29,
          "question_text": "We could barely get any information at the airport. ……..people seemed to have …… idea about the flights.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Many / any"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "A lot of / any"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Few / no"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Only a few / some"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Few / no"
        },
        {
          "id": 30,
          "question_text": "……… his friends speaks any English.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Some"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "All"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Many"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Neither of"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "None of"
        },
        {
          "id": 31,
          "question_text": "These differences between two photographs ……… with the help of Photoshop.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "should remove"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "have to remove"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "could have been removed"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "must have removed"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "could have been removed"
        },
        {
          "id": 32,
          "question_text": "New legislation ………in congress but it ………by many.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "was introduced / wasn't accepted"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "was introduced / didn't accept"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "is introduced / won't accept"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "introduced / hadn't been accepted"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "was introduced / wasn't accepted"
        },
        {
          "id": 33,
          "question_text": "Mike has been told he will have to pay the fine ---- his high rank in the military.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "even if"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "furthermore"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "despite"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "on purpose that"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "despite"
        },
        {
          "id": 34,
          "question_text": "The economy in China is booming; ……. many foreign investors are planning to enter China's market.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Nonetheless"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "so as to"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "in addition to"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "that's why"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Nonetheless"
        },
        {
          "id": 35,
          "question_text": "I wish you ……… making that noise. It's bothering me.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "would stop"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "are going to stop"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "stop"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "can stop"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "would stop"
        },
        {
          "id": 36,
          "question_text": "…… more help, I could call my neighbor.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Needed"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Should I need"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "I have needed"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "I should need"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Should I need"
        },
        {
          "id": 37,
          "question_text": "If you plan to take a long trip in the car, you must get a full tank of gas or you ---- out of gas.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "have to run"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "should have run"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "had better run"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "might run"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "might run"
        },
        {
          "id": 38,
          "question_text": "If you want to get a good night's sleep, you ---- any tea or coffee in the evenings.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "would rather drink"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "don't have to drink"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "mustn't drink"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "not able to drink"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "mustn't drink"
        },
        {
          "id": 39,
          "question_text": "It is not easy for many civil servants to …………… on their salaries as the inflation rate is extremely high.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "get by"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "turn up"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "wear out"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "run over"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "get by"
        },
        {
          "id": 40,
          "question_text": "I thought the party was going to be boring, but it ……..to be the most unforgettable evening of my life.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "turned out"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "looked around"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "passed away"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "fell back on"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "turned out"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category_name": "Math",
      "number_of_questions": 40,
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 41,
          "question_text": "Every rational number is also",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "a natural number"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "an integer"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "a whole number"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "a real number"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "a real number"
        },
        {
          "id": 42,
          "question_text": "If  −  =",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": ""
            }
          ],
          "answer": "1"
        },
        {
          "id": 43,
          "question_text": "Given U = {1,2,3, … . ,15},  = {:  ≥ 8}, = {:  ≤ 4} ℎ ∩  =",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "∅"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "U"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "AUB"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "None of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "∅"
        },
        {
          "id": 44,
          "question_text": "Which are the equal ordered pairs?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "(2,4), (4,2)"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "(2,2), (4,4)"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "(4,2), (4,2)"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "all of them"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "all of them"
        },
        {
          "id": 45,
          "question_text": " = , when a, r &  denotes first term, common ratio and sum to infinity. If",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "|| < 1"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "|| > 1"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "|| = 1"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "|| < 1"
        },
        {
          "id": 46,
          "question_text": "If 21=21 then which is true?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "x≠"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "x=y"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "x+y=21"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "either (b) or (c)"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "either (b) or (c)"
        },
        {
          "id": 47,
          "question_text": "Which is not correct?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "() = "
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "( + ) =  + "
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "() = "
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "() = "
            }
          ],
          "answer": "() = "
        },
        {
          "id": 48,
          "question_text": "Which is not correct?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "() = "
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "0 0 0 =0"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "0 0 0 =0"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "() = "
            }
          ],
          "answer": "() = "
        },
        {
          "id": 49,
          "question_text": "The equation x=0 represents",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "x-axis"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "y-axis"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "the origin"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "y-axis"
        },
        {
          "id": 50,
          "question_text": "The angle between the lines xy=0 is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "60"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "90"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "120"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "90"
        },
        {
          "id": 51,
          "question_text": "Which is correct?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "= 0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ". = −1"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "= 1"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "all of them"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "all of them"
        },
        {
          "id": 52,
          "question_text": "The domain of  = () =  is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": " − {0}"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "(-2,1)"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "(-1,1)"
            }
          ],
          "answer": " − {0}"
        },
        {
          "id": 53,
          "question_text": "Let :  →  be defined by () = 10 − 7 then ()=",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": ""
            }
          ],
          "answer": ""
        },
        {
          "id": 54,
          "question_text": "If t be a positive real number then the least value of t +  is :",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "2"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "4"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "3"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "1"
        },
        {
          "id": 55,
          "question_text": "11The value of lim→  √√  is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "-1"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "1"
        },
        {
          "id": 56,
          "question_text": "The point of discontinuity of the function () = is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "3"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "6"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "27"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "0"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "0"
        },
        {
          "id": 57,
          "question_text": "If  +  =  ℎ",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": ""
            }
          ],
          "answer": ""
        },
        {
          "id": 58,
          "question_text": "If  = 2,  =  ℎ",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "t"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": " "
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "1"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "t"
        },
        {
          "id": 59,
          "question_text": "If the total cost function C=50x+5000. The marginal cost function MC is () 50 +",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "25 + 5000"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "50"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "none of these"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": ""
            }
          ],
          "answer": "50"
        },
        {
          "id": 60,
          "question_text": "The maximum value of sin ",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "√"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "√"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": ""
            }
          ],
          "answer": "1"
        },
        {
          "id": 61,
          "question_text": "The function f(x)=2-3x is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "decreasing"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "increasing"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "neither decreasing nor increasing"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "doesn't exist"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "decreasing"
        },
        {
          "id": 62,
          "question_text": "∫   =",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": " + "
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": " −  + "
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": " +  + "
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": " + "
            }
          ],
          "answer": " + "
        },
        {
          "id": 63,
          "question_text": "∫ ||  is equal to",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "2"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "4"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "0"
        },
        {
          "id": 64,
          "question_text": "If the marginal cost of a product is given by  = 8 + 6 − 3 and the fixed cost is Rs.150. The cost function is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "8 + 6 − 6"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": " + 6 − 3"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "8 + 3 −  + 150"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "8 + 3 −  − 150"
            }
          ],
          "answer": " + 6 − 3"
        },
        {
          "id": 65,
          "question_text": "The area of the circle  +  = 16",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "4"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "4"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "16"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "16"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "16"
        },
        {
          "id": 66,
          "question_text": "The following table gives the two kinds of food and two kinds of vitamin. If qty of F1=x, qty of F2=y then formulate the following problem to minimizing the cost.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "min(z) = 3x+5y subject to 4x+8y ≥ 80, 6 + 4 ≥ 100"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "min(z) = 3x+5y subject to 4x+8y ≤ 80, 6 + 4 ≤ 100"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "min(z) = 3x+5y subject to 4x+6y ≤ 80, 8 + 4 ≤ 100"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "min(z) = 3x+5y subject to 4x+6y ≥ 80, 8 + 4 ≥ 100"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "min(z) = 3x+5y subject to 4x+6y ≥ 80, 8 + 4 ≥ 100"
        },
        {
          "id": 67,
          "question_text": "Which is the measure of dispersion?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "mean"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "median"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "mode"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "range"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "range"
        },
        {
          "id": 68,
          "question_text": "Two brothers: Mr. X and Mr. Y appear in an interview for getting the scholarship. The scholarship can be provided for two persons. The probability of getting scholarship by Mr. X is  and getting by Mr. Y is . What is the probability that both of them will get scholarship?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": ""
        },
        {
          "id": 69,
          "question_text": "The equation  +  = 2 ℎ",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "infinite solution"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "finite solution"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "no solution"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "unique solution"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "unique solution"
        },
        {
          "id": 70,
          "question_text": " +  =",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "−\n2"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "\n2 − "
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "1"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "\n2 − "
        },
        {
          "id": 71,
          "question_text": "The system of linear equations 2x+3y=5 and 4x+6x=9 are",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "consistent & dependent"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "consistent & independent"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "inconsistent & independent"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "inconsistent & dependent"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "consistent & dependent"
        },
        {
          "id": 72,
          "question_text": "The degree of polynomial equation  +  +  = 0 is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "1"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "2"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "not define"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "2"
        },
        {
          "id": 73,
          "question_text": "If one root of a quadratic equation in the real coefficient is √2 then equation is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": " + √2 + 2 = 0"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": " + 2 = 0"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": " − 2 = 0"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": " + √2 + 2 = 0"
        },
        {
          "id": 74,
          "question_text": "The equation  +  = 0 represents",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "circle"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "degenerate circle"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "an empty set"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "a straight line"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "a straight line"
        },
        {
          "id": 75,
          "question_text": "If four quantities a,b,c and d are such that a:b=3:4, b:c = 6:7 and c:d=8:9, then the ratio between a and d is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "3:8"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "1:3"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "4:7"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "7:4"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "7:4"
        },
        {
          "id": 76,
          "question_text": "By selling 175 pens, a stationary store gains the selling price of 50 pens. What is his gain percent?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "40%"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "28%\n"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "50%"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "40%"
        },
        {
          "id": 77,
          "question_text": "A, B, C and D enter into a partnership. A, B, C, subscribe , , of the capital respectively and D, the rest. What is the share of profit of D if the total profit is Rs. 24600?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Rs. 8200"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Rs. 5330"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Rs. 6150"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Rs. 4920"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Rs. 5330"
        },
        {
          "id": 78,
          "question_text": "If US $1 = Rs. 78.15. How many US dollars are equivalent To Rs. 10,000?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "$127.96"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "$172.96"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "$ 196.72"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "$172.62"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "$127.96"
        },
        {
          "id": 79,
          "question_text": "The effective rate corresponding to 10% p.a. convertible quarterly is",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "40%"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "10.1%"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "10.4%"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "none of these"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "10.4%"
        },
        {
          "id": 80,
          "question_text": "The present value of an immediate annuity is; where symbols are there usual meaning",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "{( + ) − }"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "( + ){( + ) − }"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "{ −\n()}"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "() { −\n()}"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "{( + ) − }"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category_name": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
      "number_of_questions": 10,
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 81,
          "question_text": "The study of sound & sound waves is called",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Mechanical"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Technical"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Acoustics"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Sound Waves"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Acoustics"
        },
        {
          "id": 82,
          "question_text": "A river always has",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Delta"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Fishes"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Boats"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Banks"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Banks"
        },
        {
          "id": 83,
          "question_text": "Which is the international sports competition that is held only in Nepal?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Dandi Biyo"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Elephant polo"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Bhale judhai"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Kabaddi"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Elephant polo"
        },
        {
          "id": 84,
          "question_text": "Which mountain is understood by ‘Killer Mountain’?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Manaslu"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Ama Dablam"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Cho Oyu"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Kala Patthar"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Ama Dablam"
        },
        {
          "id": 85,
          "question_text": "Which of the following is necessary for ‘knowledge’?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "School"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Teacher"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Textbook"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Learning"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Learning"
        },
        {
          "id": 86,
          "question_text": "Two concepts are related in some way; establish the same relationship on the basis of the alternatives given for UTS : FDC : : WVU : ?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "YWV"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "WXY"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "UVW"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "HGF"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "WXY"
        },
        {
          "id": 87,
          "question_text": "Insert the appropriate arithmetical signs in (?,?) to establish the relation: 9 ? 6 ? 3 = 27",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "+, "
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "- , +"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": ", +"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "+ , "
            }
          ],
          "answer": ", +"
        },
        {
          "id": 88,
          "question_text": "If LIGHT is coded as GILTH, find the code for RAINY.",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "IARYN"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "ARINY"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "NAIRY"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "RINAY"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "RINAY"
        },
        {
          "id": 89,
          "question_text": "A, B and C are intelligent, A, D and E are laborious, D, C and E are honest and A, B, and E are ambitious. Which of the following are not honest?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "A and B"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "C and A"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "A and D"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "A and D"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "C and A"
        },
        {
          "id": 90,
          "question_text": "What is the missing number in the given series below?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "17"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "27"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "35"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "41"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "35"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category_name": "IT General",
      "number_of_questions": 10,
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 91,
          "question_text": "Which of the following is not a search engine?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Google"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Altavista"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Yahoo"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Firefox Mozilla"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Firefox Mozilla"
        },
        {
          "id": 92,
          "question_text": "Name of the screen that recognizes touch input is:",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Recog screen"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Point Screen"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Touch Screen"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Android Screen"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Touch Screen"
        },
        {
          "id": 93,
          "question_text": "Arrange in ascending order the units of memory TB, KB, GB, MB",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "TB>MB>GB>KB"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "MB>GB>TB>KB"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "TB>GB>MB>KB"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "GB>MB>KB>TB"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "TB>GB>MB>KB"
        },
        {
          "id": 94,
          "question_text": "What is the full form of WWW?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "World Wide Web"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Wide World Web"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Web Wide World"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "World Web Wide"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "World Wide Web"
        },
        {
          "id": 95,
          "question_text": "Junk email is also called",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Spam"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Spoof"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Sniffer"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Jmail"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Spam"
        },
        {
          "id": 96,
          "question_text": "Which of the following is used to make presentation slides?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Powerpoint"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Word"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Excel"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Internet"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Powerpoint"
        },
        {
          "id": 97,
          "question_text": "Who is the father of the computer?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Charles Babbage"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Balise Pascal"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Garden Moore"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "John Von Neumann"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
          "id": 98,
          "question_text": "Which of the following is used as memory in computers?",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "RAM"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Keyboard"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Printer"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Mouse"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "RAM"
        },
        {
          "id": 99,
          "question_text": "MS-Word is an example of ………………………",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Operating System"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Application Software"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Output Device"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Processing Device"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Application Software"
        },
        {
          "id": 100,
          "question_text": "The printed output from a computer is known as……..",
          "options": [
            {
              "id": 1,
              "text": "Soft copy"
            },
            {
              "id": 2,
              "text": "Hard Copy"
            },
            {
              "id": 3,
              "text": "Photo Copy"
            },
            {
              "id": 4,
              "text": "Paper"
            }
          ],
          "answer": "Hard Copy"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}